(
"ai_sub_version": "2.9.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch"
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 5,
"max": 5,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
もうどうなってもいいや
[Song: I don't care]
堂々巡りのファンタジー
A fantasy going in circles
アンソロジー ナゾル謎謎
Tracing the riddles of an anthology
本能のままに行動
Acting on pure instinct
鼓動に高まる衝動
An impulse rising with my heartbeat
もうどうなってもいいや
I don't care what happens anymore
当たり前のことが知りたいだけ
I just want to know the obvious things
星に願う本当の気持ち
My true feelings wished upon a star
苦し紛れの言い訳は
A desperate excuse...
いらない 意味ない キミはどう思う？
...is unneeded and meaningless, what do you think?
行き場を失ったみたいだ
It feels like I've lost where to go
心は棘の類で
My heart is like a thorn
同じことばかり繰り返して
Doing nothing but repeating the same thing
鳥籠の中で踊る
Dancing inside a birdcage
ふわっと浮んで取り繕うまで
Gently floating until I can patch things up
描いて 泣き叫んで 消えないように
Drawing, crying out so it won't fade away
魔法みたいな都合いいもの
Something convenient like magic
主人公なら起承転結
If I'm the protagonist, there's a story arc
最後はどうなってもhappy ending
In the end, whatever happens, a happy ending
それなら 好きにさせてよ
If so, let me do as I please
もうどうなってもいいや
I don't care what happens anymore
真っ逆さまに落ちていった
Falling head over heels
無重力midnight逃避行
A zero-gravity midnight escape
秘密の裏交わって虜
Entangled behind secrets, a captive
一切合切持って行って
Take absolutely everything with you
余すことなく人生謳歌
And enjoy life to the absolute fullest
混じり合う星に想い馳せて
Letting my thoughts drift to the mingling stars
月が綺麗だなんて防衛反応
Saying the moon is beautiful
この夜は全てwonder
This night is all a wonder
愛を歌う
I sing of love
もうどうなってもいいや
I don't care what happens anymore
曖昧な笑顔に揺れてる
Swaying in an ambiguous smile
キミの瞳の奥へとピント合わしてfocus
Aligning my focus deep into your eyes
誰も触れたことのない真実の園
The garden of truth that no one has ever touched
雨に濡れたカラダ
A body drenched in rain
ざわつく ぎらつく
Restless, glittering
簡単じゃないから
Because it's not simple
もっともっともっともっと盲目に
More, more, more, more blindly
狂ってブワッと曝け出すように
Going mad and exposing it all at once
1,2の3でココロlife full
On the count of 1, 2, 3, my heart is full of life
魔法みたいな都合いいもの
Something convenient like magic
そんなもんだって縋りつきたい
I want to cling to even something like that
諦めちゃうのはもうbad ending
Giving up now would be a bad ending
なけなしの勇気を
With what little courage I have left
もうどうなってもいいや
I don't care what happens anymore
火花みたいに燃えた証
The proof that burned like a spark
いつの日か忘れちゃって
Will be forgotten someday
「儚いね」なんて感情の栞はさんで
Inserting a bookmark of emotion saying "How fleeting"
特別になるんだろう
It will surely become special
真っ当では受け流されて
Being brushed off in a decent way...
ミッドナイト飛行を 温もり感じる距離まで引き寄せて
Midnight flight, pulling it in until I can feel its warmth...
月の涙が降ったこの夜は まるで Stranger I will shake up
This night, showered in moon tears, is just like a stranger... I will shake up.
真っ逆さまに落ちていった ミッドナイト飛行を
Falling headfirst into the midnight flight...
秘密の夜が交ざり合って 虜
The secret nights mix together, making me a captive.
一切合切持って行って 歪む私の人生を
Take absolutely everything away, my warped life...
交ざり合う星に 想い馳せて
Letting my thoughts wander to the blending stars.
月が綺麗だなんて ことは忘れて Wander... I will shout
Forget about things like 'the moon is beautiful', wander... I will shout.
堂々巡りのファンタジー 遊び遊ばれの狂騒曲
A carousel of fantasy, a rhapsody of playing and being played with.
アンバランスのままに 踊るように高まる衝動
An unbalanced, dance-like swelling urge.
もう どうなってもいいや
I don't care what happens anymore.
ビビデバ
[Song: Bibideba]
つまんないって 散々だね 奇跡願ってるだけの人生
How boring, it's just terrible, a life of just wishing for miracles.
うつむいてるだけで宙 宙 宙 トリック無しのマジのマジック
Just looking down, floating in space... A real magic with no tricks.
I wanna be freeだ 有るままでいいじゃん
I wanna be free, just as I am is fine, right?
冷めないで まだ終わらないで ヘイ 達人 ちょっと宇宙まで
Don't cool down, don't end yet! Hey expert, take me to space!
今日のシーンは 音を立てて 夜を急かす 名もない今日
Today's scene makes a sound, hurrying the night of this nameless today.
人生は 一瞬にして 解ける魔法 それならば
Life is a magic that unravels in an instant... If so,
駆け抜けて ファイナルストーリー
let's run through to the final story!
お邪魔な街遊びの途中
Right in the middle of our city escapade...
Just drive! 私を大変身メイクアップ 我が儘に 毎日 煌めきにチューチュー
Just drive! Make me over completely! Selfishly kissing the sparkle every day!
シャレオツなマッチで ラストダンス さよなら群青 パレットから
A last dance in a stylish match, goodbye ultramarine from the palette!
いつか喝采喰らうフロアに 皆々ご唱和あれ
To the floor that will one day receive applause, everyone, sing along!
ビビデバビビデブーは ビビデバビビデブーは yeah
Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo, Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo, yeah!
こらえきれなくてもしょうがないから シュート オン ザ トゥナイト
Even if you can't hold back, there's nothing you can do, so shoot on the tonight!
ビビデバビビデブーは ビビデバビビデブーは yeah
Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo, Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo, yeah!
どうせ明日もないならば 12に踊ったもん勝ちでしょう
Since there might not even be a tomorrow anyway, dancing till 12 makes you the winner, right?
D-D-Dance! 右左 どんな問題も解決は1つ
D-D-Dance! Left and right! Every problem has just one solution!
正解も間違いも愛す 本当の私の理想
Loving both correct and incorrect, my true ideal.
嗚呼 なんて世界は限界の気配がして 踊るただ信じちゃ心配？
Ah, this world feels like it's reaching its limit, so I just dance—
じゃあ今すぐ Jumping! Jumping!
worried about believing? Then start jumping, jumping right now!
チックチックボン チックチックボン イライラがキキキキだ
Tick-tick-boom! Tick-tick-boom! The frustration is critical!
ギリギリ爆発 君にたった今 発信してしまおうか
On the verge of exploding, should I broadcast to you right now?
まだまだビビる 選択に御乱心 一発じゃちっとも足りないわ
Still flinching, losing my mind over choices! One shot is not nearly enough...
遂に導き出した君にアンサー 灰になるまで踊るよ
Finally derived the answer to you, I'll dance until I turn to ash!
お邪魔な街遊びの途中
Right in the middle of our city escapade......
Just drive! 私を大変身メイクアップ 我が儘に 毎日 煌めきにチューチュー
Just drive! Make me over completely! Selfishly kissing the sparkle every day!
シャレオツなマッチで ラストダンス さよなら群青 パレットから
A last dance in a stylish match, goodbye ultramarine from the palette!
いつか喝采喰らうフロアに 皆々ご唱和あれ
To the floor that will one day receive applause, everyone, sing along!
ビビデバビビデブーは ビビデバビビデブーは yeah
Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo, Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo, yeah!
こらえきれなくてもしょうがないから シュート オン ザ トゥナイト
Even if you can't hold back, there's nothing you can do, so shoot on the tonight!
ビビデバビビデブーは ビビデバビビデブーは yeah
Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo, Bibbidi-Bobbidi-Boo, yeah!
どうせ明日もないならば 12に踊ったもん勝ちでしょう
Since there might not even be a tomorrow anyway, dancing till 12 makes you the winner, right?
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
ということで 2曲お届けさせていただきました 皆さん、楽しんでますか？
And with that, I have delivered two songs. Everyone, are you enjoying yourselves?
今回は全編アコースティック編成ということで 今までの生誕ライブにはない しっとりとしたテイストでお送りしていこうと思いますよ
Since this whole concert is an acoustic setup, I thought we'd bring you a gentle and mellow vibe unlike any of my previous birthday lives!
8周年の感謝の気持ちを込めて じっくりと音楽に浸ってもらえると嬉しいです
With feelings of gratitude for my 8th anniversary, I hope you can fully immerse yourselves in the music!
それでは次の曲聴いてください 月に向かって撃て
Now, please listen to the next song: Shoot for the Moon!
月に向かって撃て
Shoot for the Moon
眺めているばかり
I do nothing but watch.
手を伸ばして思い出す
I stretch out my hand and remember.
繋ぎたくはないよね
We don't want to connect, do we?
聞かせたい声
The voice I want you to hear.
幾多もの可能性だ
There are countless possibilities.
君が誰なんだか知った
I found out who you are.
証明しよう僕ら
Let us prove it...
本当はどうしたい？
What do we really want to do?
逃げたいと耳塞いだ
I plugged my ears, wanting to run away.
しかも心臓を叩いてた
And yet, my heart was still beating.
未来
The future...
変わらない表情に
Plunge a knife
ナイフを突き立てて
into that unchanging expression!
情熱は月に向かって撃て スナイパー
Aim your passion at the moon and shoot, sniper!
未来はそうやら君次第
The future is apparently up to you.
喉が渇いたって
Even if my throat gets dry,
後悔は無いわ
I have no regrets!
擦り傷を埋めるの
Cover up the scratches,
泣いてないパーセント
with a percentage of not crying.
小指には正解を
Put the correct answer on your pinky.
本当はどうしたいんだっけ？
What was it we really wanted to do?
合図してハート射抜く 音に乗せて
Signal and shoot through the heart, set it to the sound.
Ah ah, fly me to the moon
Ah ah 一番乗りで噛み付くの
Ah ah, I'll be the first to bite.
Ah ah, fly me to the moon
Ah ah
ぶつかった壁も
Even the walls we hit,
ぶつげ合った悔しさも
and the frustration we threw at each other,
無邪気さに手貸す
lend a hand to innocence,
絶対になれ
and become an absolute!
もしも人生がゲームなら
If life is a game,
何回だって立ち上がるだけ 逆に
I'll just stand up as many times as it takes, conversely.
ねえ 大人用のアトラクションで
Hey, on this attraction for adults,
タッチダウン ダウン ダウン
touchdown, down, down!
臆病も好きに燃やしていけ ラスター
Burn your cowardice as you like, luster!
まだ見ぬ朝は君次第
The morning we haven't seen yet is up to you.
夜目を照らすアタック
An attack to illuminate the night,
後先はいいじゃん
who cares about the consequences?
吸い込んで一息
Inhale and take a breath,
泣いてないパーセント
with a percentage of not crying.
甘い罠も撃ち抜いて
Shoot through even sweet traps.
本当はどうしたいんだっけ？
What was it we really wanted to do?
合図してハート射抜く 駆け抜けて
Signal and shoot through the heart, run through!
証明しよう 届くまで
Let's prove it, until it reaches.
情熱は月に向かって撃て スナイパー
Aim your passion at the moon and shoot, sniper!
未来は今日も僕ら次第
The future is up to us again today.
誰が笑ったって
No matter who laughs,
後悔は無いわ
I have no regrets!
擦り傷を埋めるの
Cover up the scratches,
泣いてないパーセント
with a percentage of not crying.
小指には正解を
Put the correct answer on your pinky.
本当はどうしたいんだっけ？
What was it we really wanted to do?
合図してハート射抜く 音に乗せて
Signal and shoot through the heart, set it to the sound.
Ah ah, fly me to the moon
Ah ah 一番乗りで噛み付くの
Ah ah, I'll be the first to bite.
Ah ah, fly me to the moon
Ah ah 飛び込んでいけ噛み付くの
Ah ah, jump in and bite!
Ah ah, fly me to the moon
Ah ah あなただけに fly me to the moon
Ah ah, only for you, fly me to the moon.
Ah ah, fly me to the moon
Ah ah
綺麗事を吐くその口が君の事を苦しめるから
Because that mouth speaking platitudes only brings you suffering...
同じ言葉ばかりの日々に
In days filled with nothing but the same old words,
君を求めて寄り添い合うの
I seek you out, and we huddle close.
ひしめき合うカラーフィルターを
Sending crowded color filters
送って笑い合って
to each other, laughing together.
散々恨んだ虚ろな世界は
Though this hollow world we resented so much
十分なりの生き方なのに
is a perfectly adequate way of living,
完璧な思考に縛られたままで
while still bound by perfect thoughts...
強がる個性に
Biting my lip
唇を噛む 分かってない
at my stubborn individuality, you don't understand.
あぁ、そぶりをしてばかり
Ah, always just putting on an act...
綺麗事を吐くその口が
Because I hate that mouth
嫌いだから歌を歌うんだ
that speaks platitudes, I sing this song.
歪んでいるその顔が
That distorted face of yours
僕の事を曇らせる
clouds my heart.
こんな声だって 伝わらなくて
Even if a voice like this doesn't reach you,
もっと完璧な 言葉を紡ぎたくて
I want to spin even more perfect words.
ずっと欲張って きっと間違って
Always greedy, surely mistaken,
今日も底に落ちる
falling to the bottom again today.
浮かんで
Floating up...
不完全な朝
An imperfect morning...
本音も言えない日常にはただ
In a daily life where I can't express my true feelings, there is only...
「理想なんて」と嘲け笑う声
...a voice mocking, saying "as if ideals matter."
言い返す言葉も選べずに
Unable to even choose the words to talk back,
ただ増していく痛み
the pain simply continues to grow.
虚勢を張る衝動で隠して
Hiding behind the urge to bluff,
綺麗なままで生きてたいのか
do you want to live remaining beautiful?
諦めを塗り重ねて
Layering resignations over and over,
「本当」が見えなくなってしまうんだ
the "truth" ends up becoming completely invisible.
綺麗事を吐くその口が
The mouth that spouts pretty words...
Because I hate that mouth...
嫌いだから 歌を歌うんだ
...that spouts pretty words, I sing my song.
諦めているその顔が
Because that resigned face...
君の事苦しめる
...is what is making you suffer.
こんな声だって伝わらなくて
Even if a voice like this won't reach you,
もっと完璧な言葉を紡ぎたくて
and I want to spin more perfect words,
ずっと欲張ってきっと間違えて
always being greedy and surely making mistakes,
それでも歌おう
even so, let's sing,
不完全だから
because we are imperfect.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
楽しんでますか？
Are you guys enjoying it?
さあ、みんなね、武道館再演で出したあの重大発表のティザー
Now, everyone, regarding that major announcement teaser shown during the Budokan playback...
あの内容が気になっている頃なのではないでしょうか
...aren't you all getting quite curious about its contents by now?
それから、みんな、もちろん見つけてくれましたよね？
Also, did you all find it, of course?
先週の月曜日から、ある場所で屋外広告もね、出ていたりして
Since last Monday, outdoor advertisements have also been up in a certain place,
きっと今頃ね、「何が起きるんだ！」って
and by now, you're probably wondering, "What's going to happen?!"
ただならぬ空気を皆さん感じて、どぎまぎしているんじゃないかなと思うんですけれども
I think you're all feeling this unusual atmosphere and are feeling quite flustered.
まずはね、言葉じゃなくて、今日の告知に向けて
But first, instead of using words, in preparation for today's announcement,
音楽に込めてみんなに伝えたいなと思い、こういう編成で今回やらせてもらっております。
I wanted to convey it to you all through music, which is why we are performing with this acoustic setup today.
アコースティックってなんかエモくて、今までのことをこう、思い返すような
An acoustic setup feels somewhat emotional, as if looking back on everything up until now...
なんかノスタルジーな気持ちになったりしますよね。
...and it makes you feel kind of nostalgic, doesn't it?
いつもはテンションを上げてくれるようなあの曲が、今日はね、また違った形でみんなに響いたらいいなと思って
I thought it would be wonderful if songs that usually pump up your energy could reach you in a different way today,
歌わせていただいております。
...so I am singing them for you.
楽曲のアレンジもそうだし、この生誕配信自体もそうだし
The song arrangements, and this birthday stream itself,
新しい一面を見せながらも、何より、この8年間
while showing a new side of myself, most of all, during these eight years...
みんなと一緒にやってきた、紡いできた絆みたいなものが
...the bond we've built and spun together with all of you...
しっかり感じられるライブにできたら嬉しいです。
...is something I hope you can deeply feel in this live concert.
それでは、次の曲に行きましょう。
Well then, let's move on to the next song.
ムーンライト
Moonlight.
どこまで歩こうよ、裸足で
Let's walk as far as we can, barefoot,
小さな幸せを見つけて
finding little moments of happiness.
湿った月が窓をのぞきこむ
The damp moon peeks through the window,
「こっちにおいで」と笑った
laughing, "Come over here."
お互い様なんだよね 案外
It's mutual after all, unexpectedly,
分かり合えない部分も安牌
even the parts we can't understand are safe.
月明かりを見送った残像
The remaining image of the moonlight we saw off,
誰かにとっての普通をしよう
let's do what is normal to someone else.
私達を踊らせてよ ムーンライト
Let us dance, oh moonlight,
ねえ、こっちで遊ぼう、さあ、にい、さい
Hey, let's play over here, three, two, one,
隠し事ばっかりのいーさい
full of secrets, everything's fine.
歩いていこう
Let's walk on,
街あかりを奪って
stealing the city lights,
月で待ち合わせ
and meeting up on the moon.
届きそうで届かない
Just out of reach, yet so close,
あなたはムーンライト
you are the moonlight.
わけもなく寂しい夜が来て
For no reason, a lonely night comes,
古くなっていく記憶の上で
upon my fading memories.
堂々巡りなんだから厄介
It's a endless circle, so it's troublesome.
まだやることばっかで busy だけど、優に
I'm still busy with so much to do, but easily...
あの光の上 どこか遠い方へ
atop that light, somewhere far away.
このメロウな今日をずっと動いていこう
Let's keep moving through this mellow today.
尽きない悩みの種 話を聞かせて
Tell me about your endless troubles,
私とあなただけの世界で
in a world that belongs only to you and me.
あの一等星になって 街をハイジャックしようぜ
Let's become that first-magnitude star and hijack the city.
このメロウな今日をずっと動いていこう
Let's keep moving through this mellow today.
穴だらけの心で あなただけを想って
With a heart full of holes, thinking only of you,
眠れそうで眠れない こんな夜は
almost asleep but unable to sleep on a night like this.
私と踊ってムーンライト こっちで遊ぼう寂しがり
Dance with me, Moonlight, let's play over here, lonely heart.
隠し事ばっかの夜ね こっちで遊ぼうよ midnight
It's a night full of secrets, let's play over here, midnight.
街あかりを奪って
Stealing the city lights,
月で待ち合わせ
we meet up on the moon.
届きそうで届かない
Just out of reach, yet so close,
あなたはムーンライト
you are the moonlight.
遠くまで歩こうよ裸足で 小さな幸せを見つけて
Let's walk far barefoot, finding little bits of happiness.
閉め切った月夜の窓を 開けて、笑って
Open the tightly closed window of the moonlit night and smile.
堂々巡りなんだよね何回 分かり合えない部分も曖昧_
We go in circles how many times, leaving the parts we can't share ambiguous.
月明かりを巡った残像 私にとっての普通でいよう
An afterimage lingering in the moonlight, let's stay normal in my own way.
実は、ここからスペシャルゲストに来てもらっています。
Actually, from here on, we have a special guest joining us.
あっちで こっちで 踊って
Dancing here, dancing there,
君ははたりばかり かまして 僕は
you do nothing but bluff, and I...
夜を待つよ
wait for the night.
このままじゃどんどんダメになりそう
At this rate, I'll slowly ruin myself.
夜を待つよ 夜を待つよ
I wait for the night, I wait for the night.
もっと混沌の海が理想
A more chaotic sea would be ideal.
夜を待つよ 待つよ
I wait for the night, I wait.
美しいホントよりも 汚した
Rather than a beautiful truth, I want a tainted...
夜を待つよ
...night to wait for.
君を待つよ
I wait for you.
今は待つのよ
For now, I'll wait.
いつかきっときっかけは来るのよ
Someday, surely, the opportunity will come.
唇でゆっくり ゆっくり 騙して
Slowly, slowly deceive me with your lips.
ぼくはポップでチープなふりして
I pretend to be cheap and pop,
真夜中までを泳いでは
and swim until midnight.
君の目はうっとり うっとり 嗤って
Your eyes mock me, utterly spellbound.
導火線が燃える中で今
Now, as the fuse burns,
嘘をつくの
I will tell a lie.
夜が来るまでは
Until the night comes.
呼びかける数千年前から僕ら
Since thousands of years ago, we have been calling out,
夜を待つよ 夜を待つよ
waiting for the night, waiting for the night.
君がぜんぜんわからないから
Because I don't understand you at all,
夜を待つよ 待つよ
I wait for the night, I wait.
すたりすたれた街でもいいの
Even in a desolate, forgotten town, it's fine.
夜を待つよ 夜を待つよ
I wait for the night, I wait for the night.
君を待つよ
I wait for you.
そうよ もっと切っ先を研ぐのよ
Yes, I'll sharpen the blade even more.
最後最後 絶対笑うのよ
At the very end, I will definitely laugh.
君を待つよ
I wait for you.
最後最後 笑うのは僕らだ
At the very end, we're the ones who will laugh.
だって僕は星だから Stellar Stellar
Because I am a star, Stellar, Stellar.
きっと君はもう気づいていた
I'm sure you already noticed,
僕の心の奥で描いた
what I drew deep inside my heart.
それがこれから話す陳腐な
That is the cliché...
モノローグさ
...monologue I'm about to tell you.
ずっと言えない言葉があった
There were words I could never say.
壊せない壁があったんだ ずっとさ
There was a wall I couldn't break down, always.
ふっと香り立つ朝の匂いが
The sudden scent of morning rising up...
どうしようもなく憎らしくて
...was unbearably hateful to me.
部屋の隅で膝を抱えて
Huddling in the corner of my room,
震えていた
I was trembling.
太陽なんていらないから
Because I don't need the sun,
明けないでいて
please don't let the night end.
その手を伸ばして
Stretch out your hand,
誰かに届くように
so that it reaches someone.
僕だって君と同じ
Because I am just like you,
特別なんかじゃないから
not special in any way.
そうさ僕は夜を歌うよ Stellar Stellar
That's right, I sing the night, Stellar, Stellar,
ありったけの輝きで
with all the brightness I have.
今宵音楽はずっとずっと止まない
Tonight, the music will never, ever stop.
そうだ僕がずっとなりたかったのは<,s:
That's right, who I always wanted to become...
待ってるシンデレラじゃないさ
...is not Cinderella waiting around,
迎えに行く王子様だ
but the prince who goes to meet her.
だって僕は星だから
Because I am a star.
...このままでいて
...stay just like this.
その手を伸ばして
Reach out your hand.
誰かに届くように
So that it reaches someone.
本当に大切なものは
It seems like the truly important things
目に映らないみたいなんだ
are invisible to the eye.
そう僕は夜を歌うステラステラ
That's right, I am Stellar Stellar, singing the night.
ありのまま考えないで
Just as you are, don't think about it.
今宵音楽はきっときっと止まない
Tonight, the music surely, surely won't stop.
そう僕がずっと泣きたかったのは
That's right, the reason I've wanted to cry all this time
会えない日のせいじゃないさ
isn't because of the days we couldn't meet.
救いにいく今も
I'm coming to save you, even now.
夢見がちな
A dreamy...
あの黄昏も折り畳めば静寂
If you fold up even that twilight, it's silence.
僕らの街じゃ暗がりは合図だ
In our town, the darkness is a signal.
灯を消してはじめよう幕よ開け
Turn off the lights, let's begin, let the curtain rise.
見上げ願いをあなたのように
Look up and make a wish, just like you.
変わらず在っていたい
I want to stay as I always have been.
きらめきのヴェールを
A veil of sparkling lights,
目元に箒星描いて
drawing a comet near my eyes...
瞬いたソワレ今だ！
The twinkling soirée, now is the time!
寝息を立てる太陽の目を盗んで
Stealing a glance at the sleeping sun,
大脱走さ逃げ出そうぜ
it's a great escape, let's run away.
朝未き空を跨ぐ栞を挟んだら
If we insert a bookmark to cross the early morning sky,
行かなくちゃソワレ夜が明けるまでさ
we have to go, soirée, until the night dawns.
もうすこしこのままで
Just a little longer, like this...
あの鐘の音は茜差したって止まない
That bell sound doesn't stop even if the twilight shines.
時間だ集まろう野望に喝采エールを
It's time, let's gather, send cheers of applause to our ambition.
未来の話を寂しそうに聞いてる君に
To you who listen to stories of the future with a lonely look,
誓うよ世界に魔法がなくたって
I swear, even if there is no magic in this world,
夢は続いていく
our dream will go on.
おやすみに代わるよう
To replace a "goodnight,"
鳴りやまないメロディー届けて
deliver the melody that won't stop ringing.
見逃すなソワレ僕らは目撃者だ
Don't miss it, soirée, we are the witnesses.
蒼穹に手を伸ばした
We reached our hands out to the blue sky.
水平線がうたた寝したって
Even if the horizon takes a nap,
とどめなく日々を繋ぐ架け橋渡ったら
once we cross the bridge that endlessly connects the days,
いつの日かソワレ君に届くまでさ
someday, soirée, until it reaches you,
何度でも呼び声を
call out my voice, any number of times.
【star tail】
[star tail]
消えない軌跡辿って
Following the unending trajectory...
【star tale】
[star tale]
幾星霜の果てへどこまでも
To the end of many years, anywhere.
一晩じゃ語り尽くせない悲劇も
Even a tragedy that can't be fully told in one night,
一晩中語り明かせたら喜劇になってゆく
if we can talk all through the night, it will become a comedy.
【star tail】 聞かせてよ
[star tail] Let me hear it.
【star tail】 一筋の
[star tail] A single streak of...
【star tale】
[star tale]
瞬いたソワレ今だ！
The twinkling soirée, now is the time!
寝息を立てる太陽の目を盗んで
Stealing a glance at the sleeping sun,
大脱走さ逃げ出そうぜ
it's a great escape, let's run away.
朝未き空を跨ぐ栞を挟んだら
If we insert a bookmark to cross the early morning sky,
約束だソワレ僕が眠るまでは
it's a promise, soirée, until I fall asleep.
何度でもまた明日
I'll see you again tomorrow, any number of times.
拝啓、ソワレ 君へ詠み継がれる
Dear, soirée, passed on to you...
僕たちの物語
is our story.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
以上、星街すいせいでした！
That's all from Hoshimachi Suisei! Thank you!
本日のカット以上です！お疲れ様でした！
That's all for today's cut! Great job, everyone!
お疲れ様でした！ / お疲れ様です！
Great job, everyone! / Great job!
足元お気をつけください
Please watch your step.
暗くなってます お気をつけください
It's gotten dark, please watch your step.
お疲れ様でした！
Great job, everyone!
Great job!
お疲れ様です。配信見てくれてますか？
Great job. Are you watching the stream?
もちろん。本当に、お疲れ様です。
Of course. Seriously, great job.
このあと、あの件発表してきます。
After this, I'll go announce *that* matter.
胸を張って、自信を持ってお話ししてきてください。
Please speak with your head held high and with confidence.
はい、頑張ります！
Yes, I'll do my best!
あらためて、8周年記念・生誕配信を見てくれて、本当にありがとうございました。
Once again, thank you so much for watching my 8th anniversary and birthday stream.
今日は私、星街すいせいから、みなさんに重大な発表があります。
Today, I, Hoshimachi Suisei, have a major announcement to make to all of you.
これまで長年、カバーさん、そしてホロライブプロダクションには、本当にお世話になってきました。
For many years, Cover and Hololive Production have truly taken great care of me.
長年の夢だった日本武道館など、たくさんの支えのおかげで、夢を一つずつ叶えていくことができました。
Thanks to all of their support, I was able to fulfill my dreams one by one, including Nippon Budokan, which was a long-time dream of mine.
感謝の気持ちを伝えられる機会が、これまであまりなかったのですが、
I haven't had many opportunities to express my gratitude up until now,
谷郷さんをはじめ、ホロライブのタレントのみんな、スタッフのみなさん、関係してくださったみなさんに、心から感謝しています。ありがとうございました。
but I want to thank Tanigo-san, all the Hololive talents, the staff, and everyone involved from the bottom of my heart. Thank you so much.
その上で、東京ドームという次の目標に到達するためには、これからどうすればいいのかを考えてきました。
Furthermore, I've been thinking about what I need to do from now on to reach my next goal, which is the Tokyo Dome.
昔に比べると、たくさんの方に見ていただけるようになりましたが、
Compared to before, many more people are watching me now,
それでも、まだまだ越えなければいけない壁がたくさんあります。
but even so, there are still many walls that I must overcome.
いろんなものと真剣に向き合い、そして考え抜いた結果、一つの大きな決断を下しました。
After seriously facing various things and thinking them through, I have made one big decision.
びっくりさせちゃうかもしれませんが、その発表を今日、この場でさせてください。
It might surprise you, but please let me make that announcement here today.
STUDIO STELLAR
星街すいせい 個人事務所設立
[Hoshimachi Suisei Establishes Personal Agency]
ということで、この度星街すいせいは、個人事務所を設立することになりました！
And so, Hoshimachi Suisei has decided to establish a personal agency!
名称は「STUDIO STELLAR」！
The name is "STUDIO STELLAR"!
今後の私の個人の活動、日頃の配信、音楽活動、メディア出演、タイアップ、グッズ展開などなど、すべてこのSTUDIO STELLARを拠点に行っていくことになります！
All of my future personal activities, daily streams, music activities, media appearances, tie-ups, merchandise rollouts, and so on, will be based here at STUDIO STELLAR!
と、こんな真面目なトーンで話すと、
Now, if I talk in such a serious tone...
「えっ？ すいちゃん、ホロライブ卒業！？」なんてね、思っちゃう人もいるんじゃないでしょうか？
...some of you might think, "What? Is Sui-chan graduating from Hololive?!"
安心してください！ホロライブプロダクションとしての星街すいせいの活動も、これまで通り継続していきます！
But rest assured! My activities as Hoshimachi Suisei under Hololive Production will continue just as before!
ホロライブの大好きなみんなとの活動は引き続き思いっきり楽しみつつ、個人としてのさらなる高みを目指す場所が「STUDIO STELLAR」という住み分けです。
While continuing to fully enjoy activities with my beloved Hololive friends, "STUDIO STELLAR" will be the place where I aim for even greater heights as an individual. That's how we're dividing things.
もっともっと大きなステージに立つための前向きで大きな決断なので、ぜひこれからも応援してもらえると、凄く凄く嬉しいです！
This is a big, positive decision to stand on even larger stages, so I'd be incredibly happy if you continued to support me!
ちなみに、事務所の公式SNSもできましたので、今すぐフォローしてください！
By the way, the agency's official social media is up, so please follow it right now!
IDは @ST_STELLAR_INFO です！
The ID is @ST_STELLAR_INFO!
この個人事務所設立をきっかけに、星街すいせいを構成するあらゆるクリエイティブをリニューアルしていきます！
With the establishment of this personal agency, we will be renewing all the creative aspects that make up Hoshimachi Suisei!
どんどん発表していきますよ！準備はいいですか？
I'll be making announcement after announcement! Are you ready?
それでは1つ目！長年愛用してきた星街すいせいのロゴをリニューアルさせていただきました！こちら！
First up! I have renewed the Hoshimachi Suisei logo that I've loved and used for years! Here it is!
これまでの歴史とトーンはしっかり踏襲しつつ、今の時代に、そして今の私に一番フィットする形にデザインし直しました。
While keeping the history and tone of the original, it has been redesigned to fit the current era and current me the best.
さらに！ずっと欲しかった私のシンボルマークも、なんと新しく誕生しましたよ！こちら！いかがですか？可愛いね、王冠マークになっております。
Furthermore! A brand new symbol mark that I've always wanted has also been born! Here it is! What do you think? It's a cute crown mark.
お次はアーティスト写真です！どうぞ！
Next up is the artist photo! Here you go!
はい、今回は夜の海で撮影してもらいました。これからの果てしない旅を感じさせるお気に入りの1枚になっております。
Yes, this time we shot it at the sea at night. It's one of my favorites, giving a feel of the endless journey ahead.
まだまだありますよ！実はこれまでずっとなかった、すいちゃんの公式ウェブサイトがついにオープンします！
There's still more! Actually, Sui-chan's official website, which we never had before, is finally opening!
最新情報だったり、随時アップデートしていくので、毎日チェックしてくださいね！
We'll be updating it with the latest information, so please check it every day!
そしてそして！みなさんきっと待望であろう、
And, and! Something you all must have been eagerly waiting for...
公式ファンクラブも設立が決定しました！名前は「星詠み」！
An official fan club will also be established! The name is "Hoshiyomi"!
...をファンクラブの名前にさせていただきました。
...I made it the name of my fan club.
これからも、もっとみんなの近くで、色んなことを発信していきたいと思っております。
From now on, I want to share various things even closer to all of you.
ファンクラブ限定グッズが買えたり、チケットの先行申し込みができたり、
You can buy fan club-exclusive merchandise, apply for advance tickets,
会報誌、ラジオコンテンツなどなど、ファンクラブのために色んな準備をしているので、
and enjoy newsletters, radio content, and more. We're preparing various things for the fan club, so...
入会をお待ちしております！
I look forward to you joining!
入会はこの配信終了後、21時からです！
Registrations open at 21:00, right after this stream ends!
ファンクラブができたということは...
Since the fan club is up and running...
次に何が来るかお分かりですよね？
you all know what's coming next, right?
それでは、VTRをどうぞ！
Well then, please take a look at this video!
HOSHIMACHI SUISEI ARENA TOUR 2026 "Once Upon a Stellar"
横浜 Kアリーナ横浜 09.08 - 09.09
Yokohama: K Arena Yokohama | Sep 8 - Sep 9
神戸 GLION ARENA KOBE 10.21
Kobe: GLION ARENA KOBE | Oct 21
愛知 IGアリーナ 11.07
Aichi: IG Arena | Nov 7
福岡 マリンメッセ福岡A館 11.12
Fukuoka: Marine Messe Fukuoka Hall A | Nov 12
本日 3/22 21:00〜 ファンクラブ最速 先行抽選受付開始
March 22, 21:00~: Fan Club Advance Lottery Ticket Applications Open
なんと、星街すいせいアリーナツアー、またしても開催決定！
Unbelievable! A Hoshimachi Suisei Arena Tour is happening once again!
ありがとうございます！ドドン！
Thank you so much! Ta-da!
タイトルは、「Once Upon a Stellar」
The title is "Once Upon a Stellar".
今回は、4会場5公演でお届けします。
This time, we will hold 5 performances across 4 venues.
9月8日、9月9日のKアリーナ横浜2daysを皮切りに、
Starting with the 2-day performance at K Arena Yokohama on September 8 and 9,
10月21日に、GLION ARENA KOBE、
then October 21 at GLION ARENA KOBE,
11月7日に、名古屋IGアリーナ、
November 7 at Nagoya IG Arena,
そして、11月12日に、マリンメッセ福岡A館。
and finally, November 12 at Marine Messe Fukuoka Hall A.
星街すいせい初となる、4都市アリーナツアー！
This is Hoshimachi Suisei's first-ever 4-city arena tour!
ぜひ遊びに来てください！
Please do come and see me!
お気づきの方もいると思うんですけれども、今回のライブキービジュアルも、みかぴかぞさ...
Some of you might have noticed, but the key visual for this concert is also by Mika Pikaz...
カット！
Cut!
お気づきの方もいるかもしれませんが、
Some of you might have already noticed, but...
今回のライブキービジュアルは、Mika Pikazo先生に描き下ろしていただきました。
the key visual for this live concert was drawn by Mika Pikazo-sensei.
Mika先生、本当にありがとうございます！
Mika-sensei, thank you so much!
今回も本当に素敵なキービジュアルでね、ぜひたくさん見てください。
It's another truly wonderful key visual, so please take a good look at it.
チケットは、なんと本日の配信終了後から、早速ファンクラブ先行申し込みがスタートします！
Amazingly, fan club advance ticket applications will start right after today's stream!
絶対、絶対チェックしてくださいね。
Be sure to check it out, okay?!
はい、次！
Okay, next!
実は、もう一つ、騒がれていたあの大きなプロジェクトが動き出します。
Actually, another major project that was being talked about is starting up.
それでは、VTRをどうぞ！
Well then, please take a look at this video!
再起動
[Restart]
切り裂いて　シャッター切って　進んで
Tear it open, press the shutter, move forward
見出して　引力で
Find it with gravity,
高速のパッセージ
Our high-speed passage
消えない一拍を もっと紡いで
Spinning a beat that won't fade away, more and more,
打ち鳴らせ 今日も万全で
Let's make it ring out, fully prepared today!
(2ND LIVE) PROJECT: ALLEGRO
2027.2.11 [Thu] 幕張メッセ 国際展示場 4-6ホール
2027.2.11 [Thu] | Makuhari Messe International Exhibition Hall 4-6
しばらく眠っていたあのプロジェクト、MIDNIGHT GRAND ORCHESTRAも、活動を改めて本格化していきます！
That project which has been sleeping for a while, Midnight Grand Orchestra, will also resume activities in earnest!
タイトルは、「PROJECT: ALLEGRO」
The title is "PROJECT: ALLEGRO".
日程は、2027年2月11日、場所は幕張メッセにてライブを行います。
It is scheduled for February 11, 2027, and the live concert will be held at Makuhari Messe.
こちらも本日からファンクラブで先行申し込みができるので、ぜひぜひ遊びに来てください！
Advance applications for this are also available starting today through the fan club, so please come and see us!
リリースだったり、タイアップなど、すでに色々決まっているものもありますので、
There are already various things decided, like releases and tie-ups, so...
星街すいせい、そしてMIDNIGHT GRAND ORCHESTRAのこれからを楽しみにしていってくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be glad if you look forward to the future of Hoshimachi Suisei and Midnight Grand Orchestra!
さて、すごい勢いで情報を出していきましたが、...
Well, I've put out information at an incredible pace,...
皆さんついてこられておりますでしょうか？
but have you all been able to keep up?
今日発表したことは、全部ね、次の大きな目標に向けて、
Everything announced today is towards my next big goal,
私が本当に頑張りたいと思って、たくさん悩んだ末に決断をしたことです。
something I really want to work hard on, decided after a lot of agonizing.
環境は少し変わるかもしれないんですが、
My environment might change a little, but...
星街すいせいはもちろん、これからもずっと私らしくあり続けます。
Hoshimachi Suisei will, of course, continue to be myself from now on.
これからも、どうか一緒に夢を追いかけてくれると嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします。
I'd be happy if you'd continue chasing this dream together with me. Thank you very much.
さて、それでは、最後に...
Now, finally...
3つ、まだ3つもある。3つだけお知らせをして、
three... there are still three more! Just three announcements,
今日の配信を終わりにしたいと思います。
and then I will bring today's stream to a close.
まず、1つ目！
First, number one!
今日は皆さん、お忘れじゃないですよね？
You haven't forgotten about today, have you?
私の誕生日でもあるということで、
Since it's also my birthday,
生誕グッズをもちろんご用意しております！
we have, of course, prepared birthday merch for you!
Tシャツ、ステッカーセット、アクスタ、全部入りボックスに加えて、
In addition to the T-shirt, sticker set, acrylic stand, and full-set box,
ファンクラブ限定のTシャツなどなど、
there is also the fan club exclusive T-shirt and more!
どれもデザインにこだわりましたので、ぜひ手に入れてください！
Each item has a carefully crafted design, so please make sure to get them!
2つ目！
Secondly...
星街すいせいライブツアー2024「Spectra of Nova」
Hoshimachi Suisei Live Tour 2024 "Spectra of Nova,"
星街すいせい日本武道館ライブ「Supernova」
and Hoshimachi Suisei Nippon Budokan Live "Supernova,"
この2つのBlu-rayの通常盤が予約受付開始します！
pre-orders for the regular editions of these two Blu-rays are now open!
予約は本日22時からスタートです！
Pre-orders start tonight at 10 PM!
今回のBlu-rayは以前のようなセット販売はなく、
Unlike previous releases, these Blu-rays won't be sold as a set.
ツアー、武道館、それぞれ個別での販売のみになります。
They will only be sold individually as Tour and Budokan editions.
そしてツアーのBlu-rayは、埼玉公演のみの映像となっています。
Also, the Tour Blu-ray only features footage from the Saitama concert.
ただし、特典映像として、他のツアー公演の楽曲も一部収録されております。
However, some songs from other tour stops are included as bonus footage.
ゲストパートとか！
Like guest performances!
何が収録されているかは、ぜひBlu-rayでチェックしてみてください！
Please check the Blu-rays to see what's included!
なお、今回は去年販売したBlu-rayとは仕様が少し異なり、
Note that the specs this time are slightly different from last year's Blu-rays.
ツアーBlu-rayの特典映像以外の特典は付属していませんのでご注意ください。
Please be aware that there are no bonuses included other than the bonus footage on the Tour Blu-ray.
ただその分ね、お買い求めやすい価格になっておりますので、
However, the price is more affordable to reflect that...
詳しくは特設サイトや公式X、公式Twitterをチェックしてください！
so please check the special website or our official X—official Twitter—for details!
そして、3つ目！
And thirdly...
皆さん、お待たせしました！
Everyone, thank you for waiting!
毎年恒例ですが、新曲が出ます！
As is our annual tradition, a new song is coming out!
タイトルは「プリマドンナ」！
The title is "Primadonna"!
この配信が終わった後、21時半からミュージックビデオのプレミア公開が始まります！
After this stream ends, the Music Video premiere will start at 9:30 PM!
これからの星街すいせいの名刺代わりになるような、凄くテンションが上がる曲に仕上がっております。
It's designed to be a high-energy song that will serve as Hoshimachi Suisei's signature track going forward.
概要欄に貼っているURLから飛べるので、ぜひ楽しみに待っていてください！
You can access it via the link in the description, so please look forward to it!
絶対に待機していてください！
Make sure you're waiting in the premiere lobby!
ということで、以上で星街すいせい8周年記念生誕配信を終わります。
And with that, this concludes Hoshimachi Suisei's 8th anniversary birthday stream.
今日は本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for today!
新しいSTUDIO STELLARの星街すいせいも、どうかどうかよろしくお願いいたします！
Please continue to support Hoshimachi Suisei in our new STUDIO STELLAR!
それでは、まったねー！
See you later!
最後までみてくれてありがとう☆彡
[On-Screen Message: Thank you for watching until the end!]
これからも私は私らしく、みんなと共にあります。
[On-Screen Message: From here on, I will continue to be true to myself, alongside all of you.]
新しい挑戦を続けて、まだ見ぬ世界を見に行こう！ - Suisei
[On-Screen Message: Continuing to take on new challenges, let's go see worlds we've never seen before! - Suisei]
最後までみてくれてありがとう☆＝
Thank you for watching until the very end! ☆=
これからも私は私らしく、
From now on, I will continue to be true to myself,
みんなと共にあります。
and remain together with everyone.
新しい挑戦も続けて、
Continuing to take on new challenges,
まだ見ぬ世界を見に行こう！
let's go see worlds we've never seen before!
ーすいせい
—Suisei